<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psnc on North of Tyne LPC</title>
    <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/tags/psnc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psnc on North of Tyne LPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.northoftynelpc.com/tags/psnc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Services News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/advanced-services/advancedservices-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/advanced-services/advancedservices-news/</guid>
      <description> Services &amp;amp; Commissioning News  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dispensing &amp; Supply News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/dispensing/dispensingsupply-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/dispensing/dispensingsupply-news/</guid>
      <description> Dispensing &amp;amp; Supply News  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Services News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/essential-services/essentialservices-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/essential-services/essentialservices-news/</guid>
      <description> Services &amp;amp; Commissioning News  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court of Appeal upholds High Court decision on pharmacy funding cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180823-jra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180823-jra/</guid>
      <description>Court of Appeal upholds High Court decision on pharmacy funding cuts The LPC is disappointed to report that the Court of Appeal has today upheld the High Court ruling that the reduction in funding imposed on community pharmacies in October 2016 was not unlawful.
This means that the current community pharmacy funding arrangements will remain in place pending negotiations with PSNC for this financial year and beyond.
PSNC and the National Pharmacy Association (NPA) both brought Judicial Review cases following the Secretary of State’s decision to impose funding reductions on community pharmacies in October 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category M Prices</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180719-catm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180719-catm/</guid>
      <description>Category M reimbursement prices will increase by £15 million a month from August 2018, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) has confirmed.
The increase is because DHSC has agreed to cease the £15 million per month reduction in prices that had been in place to recover estimated excess margin delivered to pharmacies in 2015&amp;frasl;16 and 2016&amp;frasl;17.
These reductions had been in place since August 2017 and had been set to continue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flu Ordering</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180329-fluad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180329-fluad/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, NHS England wrote to community pharmacy contractors and general practices to advise them that for the 2018&amp;frasl;19 flu vaccination campaign, adjuvanted trivalent influenza vaccine (aTIV) (Fluad, Seqirus) should be offered to all those aged 65 and over, whilst adults aged under 65 in clinical at-risk groups should be offered a quadrivalent influenza vaccine (QIV).
Seqirus, the manufacturer of aTIV has confirmed to the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC), Public Health England (PHE) and NHS England that they can supply enough vaccine for the population aged 65 years and over in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSNC Latest News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-psnc-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-psnc-news/</guid>
      <description>PSNC Latest News We recommend that all community pharmacy contractors register for the PSNC newsletter which contains updates from their site, providing subscribers with details and links to the most relevant news articles. The newsletter covers a range of topics relating to NHS community pharmacy such as changes to contractual requirements, Drug Tariff updates and funding arrangements, as well as updates to the wider healthcare landscape. Those signed up to this list also receive price concession alerts and updates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>