<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lpc on North of Tyne LPC</title>
    <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/tags/lpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lpc on North of Tyne LPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.northoftynelpc.com/tags/lpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes of meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/minutes-of-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/minutes-of-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Approved Minutes of Meeting can be accessed by clicking the relevant meeting date.
2019 Meetings  Date Meeting Type   Wed, 06 November 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 04 September 2019 LPC Annual General Meeting
Annual Report &amp;amp; Accounts   Wed, 04 September 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 03 July 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 01 May 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 06 March 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 23 January 2019 LPC Committee Meeting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our constitution</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-constitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-constitution/</guid>
      <description>Constitution of the North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee 1. Definitions  In this Constitution –
“The Act” means the National Health Service Act 2006, as amended.
“Chief Officer” means the person employed or engaged by the Committee as its Chief Officer, Secretary, or Chief Executive Officer.
“The Committee” and “LPC” mean the Local Pharmaceutical Committee recognised by the NHS Commissioning Board (NHSCB) under the provisions of the Act as representative of the persons providing pharmaceutical services and persons providing local pharmaceutical services from premises in the area for which the Committee is formed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our contractors</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-contractors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-contractors/</guid>
      <description>North of Tyne LPC represents the following community pharmacies:
 tag or just before the end of your  tag. --  If community pharmacy contractors require a any changes to this table, please email lpc@northoftynelpc.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Community pharmacy contractors are welcome to observe our meetings.
Typically, we review progress with local commissioning, receive guests from Area Teams and other NHS and Local Authority personnel, consider new local services opportunities, deal with contract applications, discuss the progress of work carried out by the LPC Chief Officer, review the budget and management accounts, review the business plan, deal with local issues affecting contractors or matters referred to the LPC by contractors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our priorities</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-priorities/</guid>
      <description>Our Vision  Building a healthy future through community pharmacy
 Our Aims  North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee represents, supports, develops and promotes NHS Community Pharmacy in Northumberland, Newcastle and North Tyneside.
  Representing Supporting   To demonstrate to commissioners the value of service provision through community pharmacy To secure a fair level of payment and conditions for all services   To work in the best interest of all community pharmacy contractors across the North of Tyne region To strive to ensure that existing services are recommissioned or expanded   To represent contractors’ interests with all commissioners and other stakeholders To support community pharmacy contractors in delivering high quality, consistent services of benefit to patients   To respond to local and national consultations relevant to community pharmacy To support the effective implementation of new services   To respond to market entry and relocation consultations To support all pharmacies in the delivery of core services and the compliance with regulatory standards and guidance    Developing Promoting   To negotiate services and ensure community pharmacy plays an integral and growing role in healthcare provision across the North of Tyne region To promote community pharmacy to patients, public and stakeholders   To develop business opportunities for community pharmacy To build and maintain effective links with internal &amp; external stakeholders including: other LPCs &amp; LRCs, commissioners, third sector organisations, the public, and, community pharmacy contractors   To develop a sustainable vision and future for community pharmacy    To develop the skills of community pharmacists and pharmacy teams via training and sharing best practice to enable effective service delivery      Our Forward View We envisage a future where, through working in partnership with sustainability and transformation partnerships, integrated care systems and other NHS partners, community pharmacy is aligned and integrated with the local health economy and delivering a wide range of services supporting patients and the NHS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we do</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/what-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/what-we-do/</guid>
      <description>The LPC is a committee of pharmacy contractors from the North of Tyne area that has been approved (often referred to as “recognised”) by NHS England under the NHS Act 2006 as the body representing the owners of the community pharmacies in the North of Tyne area. The area of an LPC is defined by the local authority boundaries specified in the LPC Constitution.
There is only one LPC in the North of Tyne area but similar representaive committees for doctors, dentists and opticians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who we are</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/who-we-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/who-we-are/</guid>
      <description>LPC Members The members of North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee (LPC) are listed below.
The role of the LPC members is to make sure that the role of the LPC is discharged. In practice this means that the LPC member should make sure the LPC:
 has a business plan
 has a budget linked to the business plan
 manages the money contractors provide to fund the LPC and its work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190904-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190904-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 4th September 2019
Time: 12.30 – 18.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190703-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190703-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 3rd July 2019
Time: 09.30 – 17.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190613-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190613-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 6th November 2019
Time: 09.30 – 17.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190501-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190501-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 1st May 2019
Time: 09.30 – 17.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190306-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190306-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 6th March 2019
Time: 09.30 – 17.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190109-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20190109-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 9th January 2019
Time: 09.30 – 17.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20181114-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20181114-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 14th November 2018
Time: 09.30 – 17.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you are a community pharmacy contractor and you have any views or concerns you would like to share for discussion by the committee at this meeting, please email Stephen Blackman who will add them to the agenda
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC AGM &amp; Community Pharmacy Awards 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20180905-agm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20180905-agm/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 5th September 2018
Time: 18.00 – 21.00 (buffet from 18:30)
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: Book Online
Refreshments: Light refreshments will be provided
Notes:
The AGM will be followed by the North of Tyne Community Pharmacy Awards and a talk by Simon Dukes, Chief Executive Officer, PSNC.
Please come along to support your colleagues and hear Simon&amp;rsquo;s presentation that will highlight his vision for community pharmacy, the progress of the judicial review appeal and status of negotiations for the Community Pharmacy Contractual Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20180905-lpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/events/archive/20180905-lpc/</guid>
      <description>Date: Wednesday 5th September 2018
Time: 12.30 – 18.00
Location: Holiday Inn, Great North Road, Seaton Burn, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE13 6BP
Registration: See notes
Refreshments:
Notes:
If you wish to attend as an observer, please email Stephen Blackman
Papers: Agenda
Presentations None</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Community Pharmacy Awards 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180905-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180905-awards/</guid>
      <description>Following our AGM on the 5th September 2018, we presented the North of Tyne LPC Community Pharmacy Awards 2018
We had a lot of very strong entries that highlighted the excellent work done by community pharmacy in our region and we would like to thank everyone who entered and those who attended to support the winners.
The awards were presented by Simon Dukes, Chief Executive Officer, PSNC who also gave a very inspiring talk on his vision for community pharmacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Committee Appointments for North of Tyne LPC</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-committee/</guid>
      <description>The term of office for the current members of the North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee expires on 31st March 2018. Having reviewed the ownership of pharmacy contracts in our area on 31st October 2017, the new committee members will comprise eight nominated by the Company Chemists Association (CCA) and five elected by independent contractors.
North of Tyne LPC sought nominations for the five vacancies on the committee reserved for contractors who are not members of the CCA or the Association of Independent Pharmacies (AIMp).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Twitter Feed</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-twitter-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-twitter-feed/</guid>
      <description> Tweets by North of Tyne LPC   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>