<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contract on North of Tyne LPC</title>
    <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/categories/contract/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contract on North of Tyne LPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.northoftynelpc.com/categories/contract/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract &amp; IT News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/pharmacy-contract/contract--it-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/pharmacy-contract/contract--it-news/</guid>
      <description>Contract &amp;amp; IT News We recommend that all community pharmacy contractors register for the PSNC newsletter which contains updates from their site, providing subscribers with details and links to the most relevant news articles. The newsletter covers a range of topics relating to NHS community pharmacy such as changes to contractual requirements, Drug Tariff updates and funding arrangements, as well as updates to the wider healthcare landscape. Those signed up to this list also receive price concession alerts and updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category M Prices</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180719-catm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180719-catm/</guid>
      <description>Category M reimbursement prices will increase by £15 million a month from August 2018, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) has confirmed.
The increase is because DHSC has agreed to cease the £15 million per month reduction in prices that had been in place to recover estimated excess margin delivered to pharmacies in 2015&amp;frasl;16 and 2016&amp;frasl;17.
These reductions had been in place since August 2017 and had been set to continue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Leaflets</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180201-leaflets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180201-leaflets/</guid>
      <description>On 1st February 2018 NHS England published updated Approved Particulars relating to:
 Information Governance;
 the Medicines Use Review service;
 the Patient Satisfaction Survey;
 the Pharmacy Practice Leaflet; and
 Premises.
  There are no significant changes compared to the previous Approved Particulars and no actions are required by community pharmacy contractors except for those relating to the Pharmacy Practice Leaflet.
The Pharmacy Practice Leaflet Approved Particulars have been updated to reflect changes to NHS structures and guidance on use of the NHS identity; the updated requirements for leaflets no longer refer to Primary Care Trusts or NHS Direct instead referring to NHS England and NHS 111.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>