<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Support on North of Tyne LPC</title>
    <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/categories/support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Support on North of Tyne LPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.northoftynelpc.com/categories/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Smoking</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/local-services/stop-smoking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/local-services/stop-smoking/</guid>
      <description>Northumberland North of Tyne LPC does not support the Northumberland Stop Smoking Pharmacy Direct service specification. Interested pharmacies should contact Northumberland County Council, Public Health Department. Pharmacies already delivering this service should note that there is no obligation under the NHS Contractual Framework to make a supply against a NRT voucher. Pharmacies should also note that the 90p reimbursement per item is less than the NHS Single Activity Fee (currently set at £1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varenicline PGD Training</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/training/varenicline-pgd-newcl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/training/varenicline-pgd-newcl/</guid>
      <description>Newcastle This training is for Newcastle pharmacists only
Instructions for Pharmacists Please complete the following actions prior to delivering the service:
 Watch the training video
 Download and review the Varenicline PGD
 Complete the assessment questions and submit to Ann Gunning
 Await the results. If you have passed you can proceed with the following steps
 Sign and retain the Varenicline PGD
 Print and complete the declaration of competence</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training &amp; Support</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/training/</guid>
      <description> Training &amp;amp; Support </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/other-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/other-resources/</guid>
      <description> Other Resources </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Group for North of Tyne HLPs</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-hlpfacebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-hlpfacebook/</guid>
      <description>A Facebook Group has been created to support all Healthy Living Pharmacies in the North of Tyne region.
This is a closed Facebook Group so members need to be approved by LPC staff and posts are not visible to the public.
We hope this group will be useful to HLP Leaders and HLP Champions in sharing ideas and advice with each other.
Please post images of your Health Promotion Zone to inspire others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Leaflets</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180201-leaflets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180201-leaflets/</guid>
      <description>On 1st February 2018 NHS England published updated Approved Particulars relating to:
 Information Governance;
 the Medicines Use Review service;
 the Patient Satisfaction Survey;
 the Pharmacy Practice Leaflet; and
 Premises.
  There are no significant changes compared to the previous Approved Particulars and no actions are required by community pharmacy contractors except for those relating to the Pharmacy Practice Leaflet.
The Pharmacy Practice Leaflet Approved Particulars have been updated to reflect changes to NHS structures and guidance on use of the NHS identity; the updated requirements for leaflets no longer refer to Primary Care Trusts or NHS Direct instead referring to NHS England and NHS 111.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>