<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lpc Committee on North of Tyne LPC</title>
    <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/tags/lpc-committee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lpc Committee on North of Tyne LPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.northoftynelpc.com/tags/lpc-committee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minutes of meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/minutes-of-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/minutes-of-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Approved Minutes of Meeting can be accessed by clicking the relevant meeting date.
2019 Meetings  Date Meeting Type   Wed, 06 November 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 04 September 2019 LPC Annual General Meeting
Annual Report &amp;amp; Accounts   Wed, 04 September 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 03 July 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 01 May 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 06 March 2019 LPC Committee Meeting   Wed, 23 January 2019 LPC Committee Meeting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our constitution</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-constitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/our-constitution/</guid>
      <description>Constitution of the North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee 1. Definitions  In this Constitution –
“The Act” means the National Health Service Act 2006, as amended.
“Chief Officer” means the person employed or engaged by the Committee as its Chief Officer, Secretary, or Chief Executive Officer.
“The Committee” and “LPC” mean the Local Pharmaceutical Committee recognised by the NHS Commissioning Board (NHSCB) under the provisions of the Act as representative of the persons providing pharmaceutical services and persons providing local pharmaceutical services from premises in the area for which the Committee is formed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we do</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/what-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/what-we-do/</guid>
      <description>The LPC is a committee of pharmacy contractors from the North of Tyne area that has been approved (often referred to as “recognised”) by NHS England under the NHS Act 2006 as the body representing the owners of the community pharmacies in the North of Tyne area. The area of an LPC is defined by the local authority boundaries specified in the LPC Constitution.
There is only one LPC in the North of Tyne area but similar representaive committees for doctors, dentists and opticians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who we are</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/who-we-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/about/who-we-are/</guid>
      <description>LPC Members The members of North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee (LPC) are listed below.
The role of the LPC members is to make sure that the role of the LPC is discharged. In practice this means that the LPC member should make sure the LPC:
 has a business plan
 has a budget linked to the business plan
 manages the money contractors provide to fund the LPC and its work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Committee Appointments for North of Tyne LPC</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-committee/</guid>
      <description>The term of office for the current members of the North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee expires on 31st March 2018. Having reviewed the ownership of pharmacy contracts in our area on 31st October 2017, the new committee members will comprise eight nominated by the Company Chemists Association (CCA) and five elected by independent contractors.
North of Tyne LPC sought nominations for the five vacancies on the committee reserved for contractors who are not members of the CCA or the Association of Independent Pharmacies (AIMp).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>