<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on North of Tyne LPC</title>
    <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on North of Tyne LPC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.northoftynelpc.com/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Services News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/advanced-services/advancedservices-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/advanced-services/advancedservices-news/</guid>
      <description> Services &amp;amp; Commissioning News  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract &amp; IT News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/pharmacy-contract/contract--it-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/pharmacy-contract/contract--it-news/</guid>
      <description>Contract &amp;amp; IT News We recommend that all community pharmacy contractors register for the PSNC newsletter which contains updates from their site, providing subscribers with details and links to the most relevant news articles. The newsletter covers a range of topics relating to NHS community pharmacy such as changes to contractual requirements, Drug Tariff updates and funding arrangements, as well as updates to the wider healthcare landscape. Those signed up to this list also receive price concession alerts and updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dispensing &amp; Supply News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/dispensing/dispensingsupply-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/dispensing/dispensingsupply-news/</guid>
      <description> Dispensing &amp;amp; Supply News  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essential Services News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/essential-services/essentialservices-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/essential-services/essentialservices-news/</guid>
      <description> Services &amp;amp; Commissioning News  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/</guid>
      <description>In response to the announcement of the new Pharmacy Contract, The LPC has organised an event for contractors on 16th October 2019
The second contractual framework event is Wednesday 16th October and will cover the aspects of the contractual framework not covered in the first event and will also cover Primary Care Networks and include the community pharmacy awards.
Places can be booked at https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/cpcf-event-2-tickets-72767610883
The event is at the Holiday Inn, Seaton Burn and will commence with a hot three course buffet available from 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Community Pharmacy Awards 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180905-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180905-awards/</guid>
      <description>Following our AGM on the 5th September 2018, we presented the North of Tyne LPC Community Pharmacy Awards 2018
We had a lot of very strong entries that highlighted the excellent work done by community pharmacy in our region and we would like to thank everyone who entered and those who attended to support the winners.
The awards were presented by Simon Dukes, Chief Executive Officer, PSNC who also gave a very inspiring talk on his vision for community pharmacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brexit</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180903-brexit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180903-brexit/</guid>
      <description>DHSC letter published 23rd August 2018, advises that hospitals, GPs and community pharmacies throughout the UK do not need to take any steps to stockpile additional medicines, beyond their business as usual stock levels. There is also no need for clinicians to write longer NHS prescriptions. Local stockpiling is not necessary and any incidences involving the over ordering of medicines will be investigated and followed up with the relevant Chief or Responsible Pharmacist directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoptober</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180903-stoptober/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180903-stoptober/</guid>
      <description>We have been advised that Public Health England is unable to take bulk orders for Stoptober Pharmacy materials this year. Instead, pharmacies are to order their own resources directly from either the CRC or the Pharmacy orderline: 0300 123 1019.
These resources can be ordered now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUMSAS pilot extended</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180831-numsas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180831-numsas/</guid>
      <description>Updated Directions for NUMSAS have been published today, 31st August 2018, and extend the NUMSAS pilot to 31st March 2019.
Note that the Directions include a slight change to the use of the NHS summary care record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Court of Appeal upholds High Court decision on pharmacy funding cuts</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180823-jra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180823-jra/</guid>
      <description>Court of Appeal upholds High Court decision on pharmacy funding cuts The LPC is disappointed to report that the Court of Appeal has today upheld the High Court ruling that the reduction in funding imposed on community pharmacies in October 2016 was not unlawful.
This means that the current community pharmacy funding arrangements will remain in place pending negotiations with PSNC for this financial year and beyond.
PSNC and the National Pharmacy Association (NPA) both brought Judicial Review cases following the Secretary of State’s decision to impose funding reductions on community pharmacies in October 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Pharmacy Referral Service extended to 31st Mar 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180730-cprs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180730-cprs/</guid>
      <description>CPRS extended to 31st March 2019 The Community Pharmacy Referral Service (CPRS) which is part of the national Digital Minor Illness Referral Service (DMIRS) is to be continued for the full financial year to the 31st March 2019.
CPRS is still available to sign up via the NHSBSA websiteand over 370 pharmacies across the North East have now registered. We hope that all pharmacy contractors able to meet the service requirements, and, not yet signed up, will consider supporting this service that will reduce the burden on NHS urgent and emergency care services for patients requiring low acuity advice and treatment over the forthcoming winter period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category M Prices</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180719-catm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180719-catm/</guid>
      <description>Category M reimbursement prices will increase by £15 million a month from August 2018, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) has confirmed.
The increase is because DHSC has agreed to cease the £15 million per month reduction in prices that had been in place to recover estimated excess margin delivered to pharmacies in 2015&amp;frasl;16 and 2016&amp;frasl;17.
These reductions had been in place since August 2017 and had been set to continue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flu Ordering</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180329-fluad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180329-fluad/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, NHS England wrote to community pharmacy contractors and general practices to advise them that for the 2018&amp;frasl;19 flu vaccination campaign, adjuvanted trivalent influenza vaccine (aTIV) (Fluad, Seqirus) should be offered to all those aged 65 and over, whilst adults aged under 65 in clinical at-risk groups should be offered a quadrivalent influenza vaccine (QIV).
Seqirus, the manufacturer of aTIV has confirmed to the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC), Public Health England (PHE) and NHS England that they can supply enough vaccine for the population aged 65 years and over in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Group for North of Tyne HLPs</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-hlpfacebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-hlpfacebook/</guid>
      <description>A Facebook Group has been created to support all Healthy Living Pharmacies in the North of Tyne region.
This is a closed Facebook Group so members need to be approved by LPC staff and posts are not visible to the public.
We hope this group will be useful to HLP Leaders and HLP Champions in sharing ideas and advice with each other.
Please post images of your Health Promotion Zone to inspire others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Committee Appointments for North of Tyne LPC</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180305-committee/</guid>
      <description>The term of office for the current members of the North of Tyne Local Pharmaceutical Committee expires on 31st March 2018. Having reviewed the ownership of pharmacy contracts in our area on 31st October 2017, the new committee members will comprise eight nominated by the Company Chemists Association (CCA) and five elected by independent contractors.
North of Tyne LPC sought nominations for the five vacancies on the committee reserved for contractors who are not members of the CCA or the Association of Independent Pharmacies (AIMp).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay Well Pharmacy Campaign</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180308-staywell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180308-staywell/</guid>
      <description>Stay Well Pharmacy Campaign Campaign Resources The ‘Stay Well Pharmacy’ campaign was launched by NHS England on 12th February 2018. The campaign aims to raise awareness of the services offered by pharmacies, and to position them as the first place to go to for clinical advice and treatment for minor health concerns, such as coughs, colds and tummy troubles.
All pharmacies, GP surgeries and dental surgeries should have received the campaign toolkit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Leaflets</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180201-leaflets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/archive/20180201-leaflets/</guid>
      <description>On 1st February 2018 NHS England published updated Approved Particulars relating to:
 Information Governance;
 the Medicines Use Review service;
 the Patient Satisfaction Survey;
 the Pharmacy Practice Leaflet; and
 Premises.
  There are no significant changes compared to the previous Approved Particulars and no actions are required by community pharmacy contractors except for those relating to the Pharmacy Practice Leaflet.
The Pharmacy Practice Leaflet Approved Particulars have been updated to reflect changes to NHS structures and guidance on use of the NHS identity; the updated requirements for leaflets no longer refer to Primary Care Trusts or NHS Direct instead referring to NHS England and NHS 111.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North of Tyne LPC Twitter Feed</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-twitter-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-twitter-feed/</guid>
      <description> Tweets by North of Tyne LPC   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSNC Latest News</title>
      <link>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-psnc-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.northoftynelpc.com/news/20191231-psnc-news/</guid>
      <description>PSNC Latest News We recommend that all community pharmacy contractors register for the PSNC newsletter which contains updates from their site, providing subscribers with details and links to the most relevant news articles. The newsletter covers a range of topics relating to NHS community pharmacy such as changes to contractual requirements, Drug Tariff updates and funding arrangements, as well as updates to the wider healthcare landscape. Those signed up to this list also receive price concession alerts and updates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>